# **Colin Mosley**

6300 S Congress Ave, Austin, Texas | 469-442-7040 | colin.a.mosley@gmail.com <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Website</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Self-driven engineer with 3+ years of experience working in a fast-paced environment, executing company aligned goals through communication, collaboration, and critical thinking. Having multiple projects built with Ruby on Rails, React and Javascript, my ability to quickly adapt, and deliver under stress will make me a valuable asset.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails | Javascript | React | Redux | HTML5 | CSS3 | SQL | Python | JWT | PostgreSQL | Git/GitHub

#### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

## **Demolition Nutrition** - GitHub-Frontend | GitHub-Backend | Demo

A website that allows users to track their diet/exercises and perform advanced searches for food to meet dietary requirements.

- HTML | CSS | JS | React | Bootstrap | Nutritionix API | Geocoding API | Ruby on Rails | PostgreSQL
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

# Mos Bros Casino - GitHub-Frontend | GitHub-Backend | Demo

A website that helps teach users how to play blackjack "by the book" and shows the odds of a dealer/player busting on any particular hand, as well as the recommended action (hit or stay).

• HTML | CSS | JS | React | Ruby on Rails | PostgreSQL

### Maze Monkey - GitHub | Demo

A SPA that lets users explore mazes built with recursive division, as well as view the leaderboard and their own high scores.

• HTML | CSS | JS | Ruby on Rails | PostgreSQL

#### Millionaire - GitHub | Demo

A Ruby CLI application that allows the user to play a game similar to the popular "Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?"

• Ruby | ActiveRecord | SQLite3 | TTY-Prompt | Colorize | Open Trivia DB API

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### CALFRAC WELL SERVICES, San Antonio, TX

Field Engineer

March 2018 - April 2020

- Provided technical support to customers on job site; performed real time data analysis and made recommendations based off trends and incoming data
- Increased client service quality to over 95% through strict quality assurance testing, solution-driven consultations and technical analysis of frac data

#### HALLIBURTON ENERGY SERVICES, Rock Springs, WY

Field Engineer

Feb. 2017 - March 2018

- Provided technical support to customers on job site; continuously identified opportunities and made recommendations for improvements to field operations
- Performed real time data analysis to interpret how the formation reacts to the frac

## **EDUCATION**

## **FLATIRON SCHOOL**

Immersive Software Engineering Program

July 2020 - Oct. 2020

Austin, Texas

• 15-week program developing skills in Ruby on Rails, Javascript, and React through completion of multiple projects and pair programming

# THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN

Bachelor of Science, Petroleum Engineering, May 2016

Overall GPA: 3.54/4.00